Frederic and Eileen Monaghan Whitaker Papers
Frederic Whitaker Papers
- Correspondence
  - La Jolla Museum, 1969 (Box 23)
  - La Jolla Village News, 1996-1999 (Box 23)
  - Lamb, Adrian, 1962 (Box 23)
  - Lancaster Open Juried Art Show, 1959 (Box 23)
  - Lang, Ann, 1943-1944 (Box 23)
  - Lange, Herman and Natja, 1972-1983 (Box 23)
  - Larsen, Edwin (Ted), 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Laszlo, George, 1946 (Box 23)
  - Lathrop, Gertrude K., 1966 (Box 23)
  - La Revue Moderne, 1960 (Box 23)
  - Leason, Max A., 1963-1964 (Box 23)
  - Leason, Percy, 1945-1959 (Box 23)
  - Leith-Ross, Harry, 1957 (Box 23)
  - Le Vitrail Francais, 1957 (Box 23)
  - Lincourt, Evelyn, 1967-1969 (Box 23)
  - Liturgical Arts Society, Inc., 1942-1943 (Box 23)
  - Lloyd, R. McAllister, 1964-1982 (Box 23)
  - Lober, Georg, 1945-1946 (Box 23)
  - Logan, Kickapoo, 1971-1973 (Box 23)
  - Lovell, Tom, 1990-1997 (Box 23)
  - Lovoos, Janice, relating to her book on Whitaker
    - [General], 1965-2002 (Box 23)
    - [General, cont.], 1965-2002; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 24)
    - Captions, 1970 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 24)
    - Reference material, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Loring, Ginny (Mrs. Paule), 1959-1969 (Box 24)
  - Longheed, Robert E., 1957-1974 (Box 24)
  - Lowe Foundation, 1954-1955 (Box 24)
  - Lowell Art Association, 1961 (Box 24)
  - Lukits, Theo N., undated (Box 24)
  - Lulz, Dan, 1968 (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous - M, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Maccoy, Guy, 1973-1974 (Box 24)
  - MacDowell Colony, 1968-1969 (Box 25)
  - MacLeod, Robert, 1965-1993 (Box 25)
  - Macomber, Allison, 1950 (Box 25)
  - Madsen, Roy and Barbara, 1971 (Box 25)
  - Mahoney, Charles A., 1984-1988 (Box 25)
  - Manno, Joseph, undated (Box 25)
  - Marans, Moissaye, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Marblehead Arts Association, 1952 (Box 25)
  - Martin, Linda Whitaker, 2003-2005 (Box 25)
  - Mary Moore Gallery, 1987 (Box 25)
  - Mason, Roy, 1950-1973; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Massachusetts College of Art (Mass Art), 1998-2003 (Box 25)
  - Maxwell, John, 1977-1983 (Box 25)
  - McCann, Mrs. Charles, 1971-1972 (Box 25)
  - McCleery-Cumming Company, Inc., 1969 (Box 25)
  - McGrew, R. Brownell, 1971 (Box 25)
  - Meier, Henry, 1967-1972 (Box 25)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1950-1985 (Box 25)
  - Meyer, Susan, 1971-1975 (Box 25)
  - Miller, Barse, 1952-1968 (Box 25)
  - Miller, Gerhard, 1963-1969 (Box 26)
  - Millsap, Darrell W., See Millsap & Kinyon.
  - Millsap & Kinyon, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Mingei Museum, 1996-2003 (Box 26)
  - Mint Museum, undated (Box 26)
  - Mississippi State College for Women, 1965 (Box 26)
  - Moddie, John, 1963 (Box 26)
  - Mofchum, Gerald, 1963-1968 (Box 26)
  - Mongerson Gallery, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Monjo, Enrique, 1956-1963 (Box 26)
  - Monroe, Lee and Barbara ("Bobbie"), 1985; 1994,; 2004 (Box 26)
  - Montclair Art Museum, 1946 (Box 26)
  - Montgomery, Jack, 1965-1973 (Box 26)
  - Morgan, Neil, 1979-2004 (Box 26)
  - Mueller, Chris, 1971 (Box 26)
  - Muganini, Joseph, 1974 (Box 26)
  - Municipal Art Society, 1946-1947 (Box 26)
  - Munson, Ruth, 1969 (Box 26)
  - Museum of Art, Science & Industry, 1961-1966 (Box 26)
  - Museum of Fine Arts (Little Rock, Arkansas), 1959 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous - N (Box 26)
  - Nancarrow, Loren, 1996 (Box 26)
  - National Academy of Design
    - [General], 2000-2003; 3 folders (Box 26)
    - [General], 1956-2003; 8 folders (Box 27)
    - [General], 1959-1960; 1 folders (Box 28)
    - Changes to be considered, 1961 (Box 28)
    - Constitutional amendments, 1960-1961; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Constitutional changes, 1961 (Box 28)
    - EXH Committee, 1963 (Box 28)
    - Informative, 1960 (Box 28)
    - Membership, 1956 (Box 28)
    - Membership Committee, 1961 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1962 (Box 28)
    - Points accepted by committee, 1961 (Box 28)
    - Present Constitution, 1960 (Box 28)
    - Watercolor Committee, 1948 (Box 28)
  - National Arts Club, 1964-1980; 2 folders (Box 28)
  - National Council for U.S. Art, Inc., 1955 (Box 28)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, 1956 (Box 28)
  - National Orange Show Exhibition, 1970 (Box 28)
  - National Sculpture Society, 1951-1958 (Box 28)
  - National Society of Mural Painters, 1945-1946 (Box 28)
  - National Society of Painters in Casein, Inc., 1955 (Box 28)
  - National Watercolor Society, 1991-1992 (Box 28)
  - Negrón, David, 1970 (Box 28)
  - Neville Public Museum, 1945 (Box 28)
  - New Britain Museum of American Art, 1961; 1973 (Box 29)
  - New England Watercolor Society, 1985-1986 (Box 29)
  - New Haven Paint and Clay Club, Inc., 1951-1963 (Box 29)
  - New Jersey Watercolor Society, 1946-1655 (Box 29)
  - New York World's Fair, 1964 (Box 29)
  - Newhouse Galleries, Inc., 1954 (Box 29)
  - Newton Galleries, 1960 (Box 29)
  - Nicholas, Thomas A., 1966-1971 (Box 29)
  - Nisbet, Robert H., 1959-1963 (Box 29)
  - Noble, Houston, 1966-1972 (Box 29)
  - Norfolk Museum, 1956-1966 (Box 29)
  - North Shore Arts Association, 1944 (Box 29)
  - Northland Press, 1969-1985 (Box 29)
  - Northlight, 1966-1982 (Box 29)
  - Norton Gallery and School of Art, 1943-1945 (Box 29)
  - Nye, Vernon, 1967-1974 (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous - O, undated (Box 29)
  - O'Brien's Art Emporium, 1972-1973; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Oakland Art Gallery, 1942-1950 (Box 29)
  - Oakley, Thorton, 1951 (Box 29)
  - Oehler, Helen, 1945-1974 (Box 29)
  - Oklahoma Museum of Conservative Art, 1963 (Box 29)
  - Oklahoma Museum of Art, 1969-1976 (Box 29)
  - Old Bergen Art Guild, 1966-1969 (Box 30)
  - Old Town Circle, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Old Town Galleries, 1967-1976; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Olsen, Herb, 1957-1968 (Box 30)
  - Ortlieb, Robert, undated (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous - P (Box 30)
  - Palm Desert Gallery, 1970-1973 (Box 30)
  - Panoras Gallery, 1957-1958 (Box 30)
  - Parkersburg Fine Arts Center, 1943 (Box 30)
  - Parrish Art Museum, 1962 (Box 30)
  - Partridge, Roi, 1972-1975 (Box 30)
  - Pauma Village Art Gallery, undated (Box 30)
  - Peirce, Gerry, 1967 (Box 30)
  - Pellew, John C., 1962-1972; 1982-1988 (Box 30)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1967 (Box 30)
  - Permanent Pigments, Inc, 1957-1958 (Box 30)
  - Petersen, Christian, 1956-1961 (Box 30)
  - Philadelphia Museum College of Art, 1960 (Box 30)
  - Philadelphia Water Color Club, 1947-1959 (Box 31)
  - Phillips, James March, 1968 (Box 31)
  - Phoenix Art Museum, 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Pike, John, 1943; 1965-1970 (Box 31)
  - Pilots Employment Agency, 1956 (Box 31)
  - Post Publishing Co., 1958 (Box 31)
  - Pincus, Robert, 2003 (Box 31)
  - Pitz, Henry, 1956-1958; 1970 (Box 31)
  - Plainfield Art Association, 1944 (Box 31)
  - Pleissner, Ogden, 1956-1957 (Box 31)
  - Portman, John Raymond (Monsignor), undated (Box 31)
  - Potts, Thos., 1965 (Box 31)
  - The Print Room, 1955 (Box 31)
  - Procter, Burt, 1971-1974 (Box 31)
  - Providence Art Club, 1939-1947; 1964 (Box 31)
  - Providence Watercolor Club, 1943-1975 (Box 31)
  - Purdy, Donald R., undated (Box 31)
  - Putman, Donald, 1967-1969 (Box 31)
  - Puzinas, Paul and Austra, 1970-1975 (Box 31)
  - Quattrocchi, Edmondo, 1961; 1996-1998 (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous - R (Box 31)
  - Raveson, Sherman, 1955 (Box 31)
  - Rawlins, Eva, 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Ray, Ruth, 1956 (Box 31)
  - Reading Public Museum and Art Gallery, 1962-1964 (Box 31)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1971 (Box 31)
  - Reed, Doel, 1967-1968 (Box 31)
  - Reed, William, 1971 (Box 31)
  - Regan, Catherine, 1979-2000 (Box 31)
  - Reid, Albert T., 1952 (Box 31)
  - Reilly, David (Reilly, Oliver & Olsen, Ltd.), 1996-1997 (Box 31)
  - Reilly, Richard, 1977-1995; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Reinhold Publishing Company, 1961-1965; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Reiss, Lionel S., 1955 (Box 32)
  - Rembert, William and Jean, 1973 (Box 32)
  - Reynard, Grant, 1954 (Box 32)
  - Reynolds, Pat, 1987-1981 (Box 32)
  - Rhode Island School of Design (RISD), 1939-1969 (Box 32)
  - Rhode Island Water Color Society (RIWCS), 1975-1984 (Box 32)
  - Richards, Walter D., 1984-1997 (Box 32)
  - Ridgewood Art Association, Inc., 1947 (Box 32)
  - Riggs Gallery, 1989-1990 (Box 32)
  - Riley, Bernard, 1958 (Box 32)
  - Riley, Kenneth, 1958 (Box 32)
  - Rochester Art Club, 1954 (Box 32)
  - Rockport Publishers, 1996-1999 (Box 32)
  - Rogers, Charles B., 1965-1967; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1942 (Box 33)
  - Rose, John C., 1973-1974 (Box 33)
  - Ross, Alex, 1968-1973 (Box 33)
  - Royal Society of Arts, 1954-1980; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Royal Society of British Artists, 1951 (Box 33)
  - Royal Society of Painters in Water Colours, 1962 (Box 33)
  - Ruiz, José, 1962 (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous - S, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Saalburg, Grace (Mrs. Charles), 1962-1966 (Box 33)
  - Sachs, Shelly, 1966 (Box 33)
  - Safford, Ruth Perkins, 1956-1968 (Box 33)
  - Sail-making, 1957-1958 (Box 33)
  - Salmagundi Club, 1943-1965 (Box 33)
  - San Diego Art Guild/Fine Arts Gallery, 1964-1969 (Box 33)
  - San Diego Art Institute, 1967-1970; 2004 (Box 33)
  - San Diego Museum of Art, 1980-2000 (Box 33)
  - San Diego Tribune, 1966-1987 (Box 34)
  - San Diego Union, 1975-2000; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - San Diego Watercolor Society, 1965-1993 (Box 34)
  - San Diego Zoo, 1999-2003 (Box 34)
  - San Francisco, 1971; various correspondents (Box 34)
  - Sanborn, Herbert J., 1932 (Box 34)
  - Sandra Wilson Gallery, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Sands, Jennifer, 1983-2000 (Box 34)
  - Saris, Anthony, 1958-159 (Box 34)
  - Savage, Eugene, 1961-1965 (Box 34)
  - Scalise, Nicholas P., 1992 (Box 34)
  - Scarsdale Art Association, 1957 (Box 34)
  - Schaefer, Rockwell B., 1943 (Box 34)
  - Schimmel, William, 1970-1973 (Box 34)
  - Schmitt, Paul A., 1969-1970 (Box 34)
  - Scholastic Magazines Art Awards, 1956 (Box 34)
  - Scott, Beth, 1966 (Box 34)
  - Scripps Memorial Hospital, 1978 (Box 34)
  - Shackelford, Lyne T., 1966-1972 (Box 34)
  - Sheets, Millard, 1964-1973 (Box 34)
  - Sheldon Swope Art Gallery, 1967-1979 (Box 34)
  - Sherman, Stowell B., 1945-1946 (Box 34)
  - Shilstone, Arthur, 1960 (Box 34)
  - Shinn, Everett, 1942-1943 (Box 34)
  - Shneour, Polly, 2001-2003 (Box 34)
  - Silverman, Burt, 1999 (Box 34)
  - Silvermine Guild of Artists, 1951-1958 (Box 34)
  - Simpson, Maxwell Stuart, 1962 (Box 34)
  - Sisson, Frederick, 1943-1945 (Box 34)
  - Sleicher, Robert S., 1965 (Box 34)
  - Smith, Bissell Phelps, undated (Box 34)
  - Snidow, Gordon, 1971-1973 (Box 34)
  - Society of Western Artists, 1966-1970 (Box 34)
  - Sonneman, Anna, 1998 (Box 35)
  - Sorel, Edward, 1960 (Box 35)
  - Southwest Art, 1975-1981 (Box 35)
  - Sowinski, Stanislaus, 1998-2005 (Box 35)
  - Spanish Village Art Center, 1969 (Box 35)
  - Spooner, Maryjane, 1976; 1995-2005 (Box 35)
  - Spriggs, Kristine, 1977-2001; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Springfield Museum of Fine Arts [Massachusetts], 1959-1964 (Box 35)
  - Springfield Art Museum [Missouri], 1963-1967 (Box 35)
  - Springville High School Art Association/Gallery [Utah], 1969-1974 (Box 35)
  - Springville Museum of Art [Utah], 1969-1974 (Box 35)
  - St. Lawrence University, 1970-1974 (Box 35)
  - St. Luke Art Guild, 1963 (Box 35)
  - St. Peter's Evangelical Lutheran Church, 1953-1956 (Box 35)
  - Staten Island Institute of Sciences, 1944-1946 (Box 35)
  - Stefan, Ross, 1979-1989 (Box 35)
  - Steinke, Bettina, 1968-1969 (Box 35)
  - Stevens, Dr. Marjorie, 1967-1968 (Box 36)
  - Stevens, Stanford, 1963 (Box 36)
  - Strisik, Paul, 1971 (Box 36)
  - Sullivan, Mary, 1992-1999 (Box 36)
  - Sundblom, Haddon, 1953-1956 (Box 36)
  - Syndicate Publications, 1953-1955 (Box 36)
  - Syracuse University, 5 folders (Box 36)
  - Szabo, Laszlo, 1961 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous - T, undated (Box 36)
  - Talbot, Vernon, 1955-1958 (Box 36)
  - Taylor, Bailee, 1988-2000 (Box 36)
  - Teague, Donald, 1957-1964 (Box 36)
  - Thielke, Luanne, 2001-2004 (Box 36)
  - Thurston family, 1955-1957; 1993-2000; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Tiffany, Paul and Ruth, 1964-1970 (Box 37)
  - Today's Art, 1963-1966 (Box 37)
  - Tompkins, Agnes (Mrs. Erwin C.), 1967-1974 (Box 37)
  - Trailside Galleries, 1973; 1987,; 1992; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Tschamber, George H., 1943-1945 (Box 37)
  - Tucson Watercolor Guild, Inc., 1955 (Box 37)
  - Twentieth Century Realists, 1966-1968 (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous - U (Box 37)
  - United States Congress
    - [General], 1959-1967 (Box 37)
    - Congressional Bill #6874, 1955 (Box 37)
    - House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC), 1955-1959 (Box 37)
    - Barry Goldwater, 1961-1971 (Box 37)
    - Hon. George A. Dondero of Michigan, 1956-1961 (Box 37)
    - Art and Communication, 1959-1960 (Box 37)
  - University Club San Francisco, undated (Box 37)
  - University of San Diego, 1944-1971 (Box 37)
  - Utopian Club, undated (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous - V, undated (Box 37)
  - Vavra, Ron, 1995-2000 (Box 37)
  - Vebell, Edward, 1961 (Box 37)
  - Village Art Center Gallery, 1948-1964 (Box 37)
  - Vogue Wright Studios, 1957 (Box 38)
  - Vose Galleries, 1953-1955 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous - W, undated; 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Walker, Gilbert A., 1962 (Box 38)
  - Ward Eggleston Galleries, 1955 (Box 38)
  - Washington Square Outdoor Art Exhibit, 1948-1949 (Box 38)
  - Washington Water Color Association, 1942-1960 (Box 38)
  - Watercolor Correspondence School (Metropolitan Group), 1951 (Box 38)
  - Watson, Ernest, 1946-1966 (Box 38)
  - Watercolor U.S.A., 1970 (Box 38)
  - Watercolor West, 1970-1974 (Box 38)
  - Watson-Guptill Publications, 1955-1975 (Box 38)
  - Weaver, Paul, 1984-2002 (Box 38)
  - Weibel, Kathy, 1989-1991; 2 folders (Box 38)
  - West, James H., 1976-1977 (Box 38)
  - West Coast Watercolor Society, 1970-1974 (Box 38)
  - The Westerners, 1970 (Box 38)
  - Westport Artists, 1950-1958 (Box 38)
  - Wheat, John, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
  - Whitaker, Eileen, 1944-1961; letters and information about her early career (Box 39)
  - Whitaker, Frederic
    - Writings, articles written by Whitaker that do not appear in American Artist; articles written about Whitaker that have not been filed under any other folder; short stories, notes and essays written by Whitaker that were not filed under any other folder; condolences written to Eileen Whitaker or "In Memoriams" published after Whitaker's death in 1980. (Box 39)
    - Condolences on his death, 1980 (Box 39)
    - Salad tongs design, 1975-1976 (Box 39)
    - Book by Janice Lovoos, correspondence and information regarding the book written about Whitaker by Janice Lovoos; See Lovoos, Janice above.
  - Whitaker family, 1939-1973 (Box 39)
  - Whitney, Edgar A., 1965-1973 (Box 39)
  - Whitney, Joseph F., 1966-1976 (Box 39)
  - Who's Who in American Art, 1958 (Box 39)
  - Who's Who in Art Gallery, 1978-1980 (Box 39)
  - Wichita Centennial National Art Exhibit, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Wichita State University, 1971-2003 (Box 39)
  - Wieghorst, Olaf, 1972 (Box 39)
  - Wilbur, Lawrence Nelson, 1957 (Box 39)
  - Wilkey, Justice Roscoe S., 1970 (Box 39)
  - Williams, John Scott, 1959-1977 (Box 39)
  - Williams, Wheeler, 1957-1965 (Box 39)
  - Wilson, Ivan, 1954-1966 (Box 39)
  - Witt, Samuel A., 1964-1969 (Box 39)
  - Wollheim-Rosequist Galleries, 1975-1989 (Box 39)
  - Wong, Frederick, 1967-1968 (Box 39)
  - Wood, Robert E., 1967-1970 (Box 39)
  - Wostrel, Nancy, 1994-2004 (Box 39)
  - Wright, Barton A., 1969 (Box 39)
  - Wright, Frank C., 1967 (Box 39)
    See also Council of American Artist Societies: Frank C. Wright, Jr. above.
  - Wurlitzer Foundation, 1969-1970 (Box 39)
  - Wyoming Valley Art League, 1960-1961 (Box 39)
  - Wyeth, Andrew, 1951 (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous - Y (Box 39)
  - Yaros, Ken, 1997-2002 (Box 39)
  - Zornes, Milford, 1966-1970 (Box 39)
  - Unidentified (Box 39)
- Eileen Whitaker
  - Awards, undated (Box 40)
  - Biography, 1955 (Box 40)
  - Book clippings, undated (Box 40)
  - Clippings, 1967 (Box 40)
  - Contract, 1980 (Box 40)
  - Exhibitions of Eileen's work, 1961-1996 (Box 40)
  - Inventory of office, 1993 (Box 40)
  - Quotes and miscellaneous, 1982 (Box 40)
  - United States International University, 1981-1983 (Box 40)
- Memorabilia
  - Address book (Oversize 3)
  - American Watercolor Society silver-handled paintbbrush (Oversize 3)
  - Book of pressed flowers (Oversize 3)
  - Brushes (Oversize 3)
  - Caricature of Fred (Oversize 3)
  - Eileen Monaghan Whitaker, personal, undated; 5 folders (Box 41)
  - Frederic's death
    - Appraisals of Fred's work, 1982 (Box 41)
    - Condolence letters, 1980 (Box 41)
    - Distribution of Fred's work, 1981 (Box 41)
    - Obituaries and tributes, 1980 (Box 41)
    - Will and Testament, 1981 (Box 41)
  - Gastebuch (Oversize 3)
  - Photographs
    - Amish and Pennsylvania Dutch (Box 41)
    - Animals, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Boats (Box 41)
    - Buildings (Box 41)
    - Canada (Quebec) (Box 41)
    - Connecticut (Box 41)
    - Corn shocks (Box 42)
    - Delaware (Box 42)
    - Donkeys (Box 42)
    - France (Box 42)
    - Germany (Box 42)
    - Gloucester (Mass.) (Box 42)
    - Ireland (Box 42)
    - Italy (Box 42)
    - Louisiana (Box 42)
    - Maine (Box 42)
    - Mexico, 3 folders (Box 42)
    - Mexico, 4 folders (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous, A-R, 3 folders (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous, S-Z (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous, unlabeled (Box 44)
    - New Jersey, quarry (Box 44)
    - New York, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Norwalk (Connecticut) (Box 44)
    - Pennsylvania (Box 44)
    - Piermont (Box 44)
    - Portugal [MISSING May 2016], 1956
    - Rhode Island (Box 44)
    - Rocks (Box 44)
    - Roslyn (Box 44)
    - Skiffs (Box 44)
    - Spain, A-C, 1956; 4 folders (Box 44)
    - Spain, C-T, 1956; 8 folders (Box 45)
    - Spain, V-Y, 1956 (Box 46)
    - Spain, miscellaneous, 1956; 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Tobacco plants (Box 46)
    - Trees (Box 46)
    - Tugs (Box 46)
    - United States, various (Box 47)
    - Unknown (Box 46)
    - Vermont (Box 46)
    - Of Fred Whitaker (Box 46)
  - Plaque from San Diego Watercolor Society (Oversize 3)
  - Postcards
    - France, 1956; 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous, A-M (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous, M-W (Box 48)
    - Spain (Box 48)
  - Records
    - Art records, 1971 (Box 48)
    - Artists known (Box 48)
    - Awards, etc., 1957; 1974 (Box 48)
    - Biographical materials, undated (Box 48)
    - Consignment papers, 1974 (Box 48)
    - Copyright registration, 1942 (Box 48)
    - Member lists, 1962 (Box 48)
    - Museums represented, 1970 (Box 48)
    - Regarding ownership of Whitaker paintings, 1957-1975 (Box 48)
    - Watercolor owners, 1976-1978 (Box 48)
  - Sheet music (gift) (Oversize 3)
  - Tape of the Horatio Alger Awards, whitaker_001; 1 reel (Oversize 3)
  - Tools (Oversize 3)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook (Oversize 4)
    - Scrapbook (Oversize 4)
    - Scrapbook (Oversize 5)
    - Scrapbook (Oversize 5)
  - Travel
    - France (Box 49)
    - Ireland (Box 49)
    - London (Box 49)
    - Portugal (Box 49)
    - Spain (Box 49)
  - War ration book, undated (Box 49)
- Printed material
  - Articles
    - About Eileen Monaghan, 1967; 1971-1975 (Box 55)
    - About Frederic Whitaker, 1939-1949; 1954-1980,; undated; 6 folders (Box 55)
  - Calendars
    - General Tire International, 1967 (Box 55)
    - New York Life Agent, 1961 (Box 55)
  - Clippings
    - About Eileen (Box 55)
    - About FW, 1931-1945; 7 folders (Box 55)
    - About FW, 1946-1960; 15 folders (Box 56)
    - About FW, 1961-1986; undated; 17 folders (Box 57)
    - About art, artists (Box 57)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
  - Exhibit catalogs
    - Catalogs, 1939-1950; 18 folders (Box 50)
    - Catalogs, 1951-1959; 13 folders (Box 51)
    - Catalogs, 1960-1966; 12 folders (Box 52)
    - Catalogs, 1968-1972; 8 folders (Box 53)
    - Catalogs, 1973-1980; 6 folders (Box 54)
    - Catalogs, 1990-2000 (Box 54)
    - Catalogs, Undated; 3 folders (Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous
    - About FW (Box 58)
    - Rhode Island School of Design (RISD) alumni publications, 1944-1945; 1956,; 1968-1969,; 1972,; 1975; 2 folders (Box 58)
- Writings
  - Articles, published/printed articles by the Whitakers
    - By Eileen Monaghan, 1959 (Box 58)
    - By Frederic Whitaker, 1947-1969; most published in American Artist, Today's Artist, or The Artist; 3 folders (Box 58)
  - Autobiography, 2 folders (Box 58)
    See also Manuscripts: Autobiography, below.
  - Biographical sketches (Box 58)
  - Drafts
    - [General], 4 folders (Box 59)
    - Guatemala (Box 59)
    - Notes on drawings (Box 59)
    - Speech, "A New Division" (Box 59)
    - Speeches (Box 59)
    - The Artist of the Real World (Box 59)
  - Essays, typescripts of essays on various topics, by FW
    - Anti-Defamation, 1974 (Box 59)
    - Anti-Discrimination (Box 59)
    - Are Americans Too Generous, 1971 (Box 59)
    - Are You A Genius? / Is It Smart (Box 59)
    - Art, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Arts Organization (Box 59)
    - Articles and Random Thoughts (complete set) (Box 59)
    - Artistic Abnegation (Box 59)
    - Assimilabilty (Box 59)
    - Barnacles, 1977 (Box 59)
    - Beauty is Where You Find It, 1971 (Box 59)
    - Beggars, 1973 (Box 59)
    - Blackmail (Box 59)
    - Booby Traps, 1977 (Box 59)
    - Can't Sleep Tonight, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Charity, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Concentration, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Conversation with My Wife, undated (Box 60)
    - Copies, 1973 (Box 60)
    - Creativity Is Not Easy, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Credo, 1974 (Box 60)
    - Cult of Irresponsibility, undated (Box 60)
    - Democracy Republic, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Dependability, 1976 (Box 60)
    - Design in Painting, 1954 (Box 60)
    - Emerging Nations, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Endless Results Follow Every Action, 1972 (Box 60)
    - The Entrepreneur, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Equality, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Equality of Privilege, undated (Box 60)
    - Everyone Needs Help, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Evolution versus Revolution, 1954 (Box 60)
    - Eye Versus Camera, undated (Box 60)
    - Fairy tale, "The Glass Mountain", 1979 (Box 60)
    - Free Enterprise, 1978 (Box 60)
    - Free Enterprise, undated (Box 60)
    - Freedom from Lice, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Free-loaders, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Friends, profiles of, undated (Box 60)
    - Genius - Artistic and Commercial, undated (Box 60)
    - Genius - Or the Tale of a Young Inventor, 1977 (Box 60)
    - The Glass Mountain, See Fairy tale, "The Glass Mountain"
    - Guilty or Not, 1977 (Box 60)
    - Habits of Unsalaried Assistants, undated (Box 60)
    - Helping Others, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Hospitality, 1976 (Box 60)
    - How a Left Wing Movement Operates, undated (Box 60)
    - How I Paint a Watercolor, 1954 (Box 60)
    - How to Get Things Done, 1972 (Box 60)
    - How to Clarify Your Thinking, 1971 (Box 60)
    - How to Paint An Outstanding Watercolor, undated (Box 60)
    - How's Joe, 1976 (Box 60)
    - I Know My Rights, 1971 (Box 60)
    - I Marched in the Parade, 1970 (Box 60)
    - Ideas Cut Two Ways, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Illegal Aliens, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Incidence of Chance, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Income tax, 1978 (Box 60)
    - The Indian Problem, 1974 (Box 60)
    - Inflation Simplified, 1974 (Box 60)
    - Invention, 1976 (Box 60)
    - It Isn't Necessary Always to Access the Blame, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Is Art A Vocation?, undated (Box 60)
    - Is Liberty a Cancer?, undated (Box 60)
    - Is Tolerance A One-Way Street?, undated (Box 60)
    - Jobs, 1976 (Box 60)
    - Justice, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Justice Can Be Bought, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Legal Punishment, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Legal vs. Intuitional Judgment, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Let's Be Neat?, undated (Box 60)
    - Let's Be Practical, undated (Box 60)
    - Let's Teach Facts of Life, 1970 (Box 60)
    - Life Is a Tough Ordeal, 1974 (Box 60)
    - Malpractice Insurance, 1975 (Box 60)
    - May we copy the work of others?, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Medical Malpractice, 1975 (Box 60)
    - Menial Labor, 1971 (Box 60)
    - Merry Christmas Amigos, undated (Box 60)
    - Metamorphosis, 1977 (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1976; 3 folders (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous and drafts, 1978 (Box 60)